Guide to the The pleasure of his company, 1966-1967
Department of Special Collections
Fay, Paul Burgess, 1918-. The pleasure of his company,
1966-1967
Special Collections M0213
Fay, Paul Burgess, 1918-.
2 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Material relating to various stages in the researching, writing, publication, and promotion of THE PLEASURE OF HIS COMPANY, by Paul B. Fay, Jr., a longtime friend of John F. Kennedy. Includes manuscript, galleys, correspondence, and notes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Paul B. Fay, Jr., 1968.
Biographical Note
Under-Secretary of the Navy in the Kennedy administration.
Scope and Content
Material relating to various stages in the researching, writing, publication, and promotion of THE PLEASURE OF HIS COMPANY, by Paul B. Fay, Jr., a longtime friend of John F. Kennedy. Includes manuscript, galleys, correspondence, and notes.
Arrangement
The various drafts of The Pleasure Of His Company have been arranged into general categories roughly representing successive stages in the work's evolution, as follows:
Handwritten Drafts.
First Typescript:
Transcripts of tapes and handwritten drafts.
Second Typescript:
First division of the work into chapters; includes several drafts of most chapters, each incorporating autograph corrections made on the previous drafts.
Third Typescript:
Essentially a complete draft incorporating all the revisions made on the Second Typescript.
Fourth Typescript:
Drafts before final editing and Kennedy Family review.
Fifth Typescript:
Final drafts with Kennedy Family comments.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Fay, Paul B., 1918-; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Kennedy, Joseph P. (Joseph Patrick), 1888-1969.; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968.; Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1929-; Presidents--United States.
ABBREVIATIONS
t.s. typescript.
c.t.s. carbon copy of typescript.
Container List
- Handwritten drafts.
  - a) Fragments on yellow legal length paper. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - b) Spiral-bound notebooks (5). (Box 1, Folder 2)
- First typescript.
  - Various fragmentary drafts. (Box 1, Folder 3, Folder 4, Folder 5, Box 2, Folder 1)
- Second typescript.
  - Introduction. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 3 pp. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 4 pp.
  - Chapter 1. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 8 pp. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 7 pp.
  - 3rd. draft. Version cut to one incident; t.s., with autograph corrections, 6 pp.
  - 4th. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 5 pp.
  - Chapter 2. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 10pp. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chapter 3. 1st. draft. T.s., with autograph corrections, 8 pp. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 6 pp.
  - Chapter 4. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 17 pp. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 2nd. draft. C.t.s., 10 pp.
  - 3rd. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 12 pp.
  - 4th. draft. C.t.s., t.s., 9 pp.
  - Chapter 5. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 12 pp. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 10 pp.
  - Chapter 6. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 6 pp. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 7 pp.
  - Chapter 7. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 11 pp. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 10 pp.
  - Chapter 8. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 15 pp. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 12 pp.
  - Chapter 9. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 11 pp. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 9 pp.
  - Chapter 10. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 15 pp. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 2nd. draft. C.t.s., t.s., 15 pp.
  - Chapter 11. 1st draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 16 pp. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 17 pp.
  - Chapter 12. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 15 pp. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 11 pp.
  - Chapter 13. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 17 pp. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 2nd. draft. C.t.s., t.s., 17 pp.
  - Chapter 14. C.t.s., 13 pp. (2). (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Chapter 15. 1st. draft. C.t.s., 14 pp. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 2nd. draft. C.t.s., t.s., 11 pp.
  - Chapter 16. 1st. draft. C.t.s., 11 pp. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., 9 pp.
  - Chapter 17. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 5 pp. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 2nd. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 11 pp.
  - 3rd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 15 pp.
  - Chapter 18. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 7 pp. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 2nd. draft. C.t.s., t.s., 7 pp.
  - Chapter 19. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 17 pp. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 2nd. draft. C.t.s., 15 pp. (2).
  - Chapter 20. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 7 pp. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 7 pp.
  - Chapter 21. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 17 pp. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 13 pp.
  - Chapter 23. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 12 pp. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 10 pp.
  - Chapter 24. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 12 pp. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 13 pp.
  - Chapter 26. 1st. draft. C.t.s., with autograph corrections, 5 pp. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 2nd. draft. T.s., c.t.s., 3 pp.
- Third typescript.
  - Xerox draft, with autograph corrections. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Fourth typescript.
  - a) Xerox draft, with autograph edit by Myrick Land. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - b) T.S. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Fifth typescript.
  - a) T.s., almost complete, with edits by Jacqueline Kennedy and Evan Thomas. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - b) Xerox, partial, with Robert F. Kennedy edits. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- OVERSIZE
  - Shirt carboard with notations by Paul B. Fay, Jr.
- Gente, March 24, 1967.
- Life, November 18, 1966.
- December 9, 1966.
- Miscellaneous sheets of corrections and errata for final draft. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Fragments of final, post-Kennedy-family edit draft. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Printer's proof. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Correspondence.
  - General File. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified (4).
    - Book of the Month Club; see Thompson, Ralph.
    - Deane, Martha; see Taylor, Marian Young.
    - Galbraith, John Kenneth. 1966(1).
    - Geis, Bernard. 1966(1).
    - Lord, Sterling. 1966(2).
    - Muheim, Harry. 1966(1).
    - McDermott, Edward A. 1966(1).
    - Nash, Edmund W. 1966(1).
    - Sidey, Hugh. 1966(1).
    - Stockman, James. 1965(2).
    - Taylor, Marian Young (Martha Deane). 1966(1).
    - Thompson, Ralph. 1966(1).
    - Tyrrell, Albert R. 1966(1).
    - Webb, Allan W. 1965(1).
    - Wilson, John. 1967(1).
  - Fay, Paul B. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Carbons. 1960(1). Draft of letter to father.
    - 1965(15).
    - 1966(46).
    - 1967(14).
  - Harper and Row. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - To Paul B. Fay. From:
      - Cade, Lisl (Publicity dept.) 1967(1).
      - Franco, Rose (Asst. to Evan Thomas).
        - 1965(1).
        - 1966(7).
        - 1967(2).
      - Harris, Stuart (Publicity director).
        - 1966(3).
      - Thomas, Evan. (Chairman, Editorial Board).
        - 1965(16).
        - 1966(19).
        - 1967(5).
      - Yates, Patricia (Production dept.) 1966(1).
    - To others: (9).
  - Kennedy Family. Xeroxes of Letters to Paul B. Fay. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - John F. Kennedy -- (11).
    - Joseph Kennedy -- (1).
    - Robert F. Kennedy - (1).
  - Land, Myrick ( Look Magazine Book Editor). (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - n.d.(2)
    - 1965(2).
    - 1966(4).
- Miscellany; including newspaper and magazine clippings; photograph of Paul B. Fay; publicity travel schedules; mimeo of 4/22/66speech by John K. Galbraith; C.t.s. of description of P.T. 109 incident, written by J.F.K. (Box 4)